The greatest comedy team in an all new collection of their
funniest moments from the rip-roaring 1920's.
The Further Perils of Laurel and Hardy is a comedy
film directed by Robert Youngson.
Film historian Robert Youngson presents a feature-length anthology of rarely
seen silent films by comedy legends Stan Laurel and Oliver Hardy.
Along with clips from many of the shorts that made the duo stars, it includes clips from a 1918 comedy starring Laurel on his
own as well as scenes from three shorts Hardy made in 1917 and '18 with his original comedy partner, Billy West.
To put the duo's work in context, the film briefly features
other comedians who worked with producer Hal Roach.
This list contains only the films that Laurel and Hardy made together.
For their solo films see Stan Laurel filmography and Oliver Hardy filmography.
Laurel and Hardy were a motion picture comedy team whose official
filmography consists of 106 films released between 1921 and 1951.
Together they appeared in 34 silent shorts,A 45 sound shorts, and 27 full-length sound feature films.B In addition to these, Laurel and Hardy appeared in at
least 20 foreign-language versions of their films and a promotional film, Galaxy of Stars (1936), produced for European film distributors.
Stan Laurel (1890–1965) and Oliver Hardy (1892–1957) were established as film comedians prior to
their teaming, with Laurel appearing in over 50 silent films and Hardy in over 250.
(Hardy also appeared in three sound features without Laurel.) Although they first worked together in the film The Lucky Dog (1921), this was a chance pairing
and it was not until 1926 when both separately signed contracts with the Hal Roach film studio that they appeared in film shorts together.
Gehring identifies their first "official" film together
as Putting Pants on Philip, William K.
Everson identifies The Second Hundred Years as the first "official"
Laurel and Hardy film in which they are presented as a team.
Should Married Men Go Home?
was the first Hal Roach film to bill Laurel and Hardy as a team.
Previous appearances together were billed under
the Roach "All-Star Comedy" banner.
The pair remained with the Roach studio until 1940.
Between 1941 and 1945, they appeared in eight features and one
short for 20th Century Fox and Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
After finishing their film commitments, Laurel and Hardy concentrated on
stage shows, embarking on a music hall tour of Great Britain.
In 1950, they appeared in their last film, Atoll
K, a French/Italian co-production.
In 1932, Laurel and Hardy's short The Music Box won the
Academy Award for Live Action Short Film (Comedy).
In 1960, Laurel was presented with an Academy Honorary Award "for his creative pioneering in the field of cinema comedy." In 1992, 1997, 2012 and 2020 respectively, Big Business (1929), The Music Box, Sons of the Desert (1933) and The Battle of the Century (1927) were
added to the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." For their contributions to cinema, Laurel and Hardy have been awarded separate stars on the Hollywood Walk of Fame.
The tone is lighthearted.